ER

EMILY ROTHMAN

ehrothman@gmail.com | 619.993.3645 San Diego, CA 92111

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Charismatic and dependable Teacher with 6 years of experience delivering educational assistance and instruction to various levels of learners.

Committed to providing students with necessary tools to achieve academic goals, instilling love of learning and cooperative teamwork. Adept in application of excellent communication and problem solving skills.

SKILLS

- Curriculum design
- Experience teaching Hebrew
- Conflict Resolution
- ESL instruction
- Classroom management
- Student Progress Report
- Lesson Implementation
- Small group intervention
- Tutoring
- Relationship building and management

WORK HISTORY

Substitute Teacher | Chula Vista Elementary School 04/2019 - CURRENT District - Chula Vista, CA

• Implement classroom teacher generated lesson plans • Classroom behavior managment • General supervision.

Substitute Teacher | Teachers on Reserve - San 09/2018 - 04/2019 Diego, CA

• Plan and implement common core curriculum •Student assessment and intervention •Parent / Teacher / Student liaison.

Pre-K Teacher | Temple Beth Israel - San Diego, CA 04/2017 - 08/2018

• Curriculum design / lesson implementation • Child assessment and intervention • Parent / Teacher / Student liaison.

Kindergarten / Pre-K Teacher / Fifth grade Hebrew 08/2010 - 06/2016 school teacher | Temple Solel Early Childhood Center - Encinitas, CA

• Lesson plan – Design / Instruction • Child development / general supervision • Parent / Teacher / Student liaison.

Child Care Worker | Ocean Air Elementary School - 08/2009 - 11/2010 Del Mar, CA

Coursework / homework assistance • Activity planning /
 Implementation • Child development / general supervision.

Fifth Grade ESL Teacher | Sutton Elementary School - 08/2008 - 05/2009 Houston, TX

 Lesson plan – Design / Instruction • Creation of specialized learning programs • Creation of student wellness programs • Increased performance of underperforming students (math, reading, science).

Student Teacher / Tutor | Elvira Elementary School - 01/2008 - 05/2008 Tucson, AZ

 Periodically assigned instructor responsibilities •Lesson plan – Design / Instruction •Creation of student wellness programs.

Substitute Teacher | Sunnyside Unified School District - 09/2007 - 05/2008 Tucson, AZ

- Lesson plan Design / Instruction General classroom mgt.
- Enforcement of general school policies.

Student Teacher | UCAT applications - Tucson, AZ 08/2007 - 12/2007

 Lesson plan – Design / Instruction •Instructor (mentor) - observation hours •Development of applied learning formats / techniques
 •Enforcement of standard behavioral policies.

EDUCATION

University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ

05/2008

Elementary Education

Volunteer Experience: Course # TTE 300

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Professional references available upon request